one can lead content life if one
invested in developing self-control more
self-control the more content you are
with what you're given the less
self-control the more of fault-finding
you have with what you're given which
means the less contentment and more of
craving for things that you don't have
so and then that's that's that's a true
principle regardless of the best
religion or the practice it's a
recognition of a certain certain amount
of self-control through restraint to
saying no to avoiding indulgence because
it is like like the similar in the
circus is like scratching the itch say
there is a skin age that it's very
personal barrage and then to scratching
it a person is developing a relief yeah
you're scratching it the person finds a
relief from the rich but at the same
time the actual act of scratching is
making the condition it's itching even
worse between the next time and that's
why there are many people today suffer
from depression for example because most
of their life
certain in Western culture we were never
Hoover never taught value of restraint
or if we were it would have been in a
kind of secondary man and black patience
is good sharing is good
all these things are good is because you
say no to yourself but you don't want
the circumstances to be doing it for you
you want to actually take responsibility
for being able to access as a degree of
control over your center self because
that's how you develop strength not not
through being forced into restraint just
because you couldn't get it your way so
there's a fundamental difference there
and because most people it's just what
we are we been taught is to go after
things you want as soon as you can get
there because of that sooner or probably
sooner than later people well but income
none there isn't much any because you get
there isn't much any because you get
tired of the chase you get tired of the
pressure you get tired of the lack of
satisfaction when you do get things that
you want why because now you want
something else so even more of it so so
all of those things result in developing
a certain numbness whereby well you're
certainly not content with what you have
and you even start giving up on things
that you could have because you're just
tired of the chase and that's that's
that's that's a rudimentary form of
depression of those that can then become
a chronic state and weigh down the mind
and all the motivation and so on but but
fundamentally a person could step
outside of any of those states just just
willingly starting to exercise a degree
of self-control in regard to things
throughout their daily life in regard to
their desires and wants and needs in
regard to comfort and luxury which is
usually taken to granted you start you
start well putting some brakes on it and
also contemplating the nature
love it mental dependence of a body
being in a comfortable situation for
example the body can be trained to start
enduring more which will make it
actually more content within with medium
or with moderate amount of comfort he
won't need any access luxurious own in
order to feel Pleasant why because it
has developed a certain amount of
resistance and training so it can endure
more but being able to do more means it
feels less so for a general idea of a
happier more content life again putting
aside any ideological beliefs infuse the
people might have the actual practice of
self-control in regard to day to day
life will result in an increasing of the
contentment with day to day life and one
is content with things one is not the
faster we got
so it's something worth developing
really then Boldwood teaching as well
because many people would be capable of
doing it many people would be able to
detect the string and then actually to
start understanding the value of it and
of that self-control but it's not
something that the person can obtain
just too near whooshing like you just
wish that you can be in a position of
control and then you become no you just
have to the repetitive drilling in
efforts gradual increase of those
restraints so recognizing what's not
necessary in your life in terms of
indulgences in terms of sensuality in
terms of comfort in terms of luxury and
then just say no to yourself for no
other reason than to just say no to it
so to that degree of what is not
necessary doesn't mean you give up
everything and you go and live on a rock
or something in a cave without any food
well that's just going to the other
extreme I'm gonna survive but just
exercising reason and intelligence in
regard to current life you got too many
things there in their life they're not
necessary and it's not needed at all and
that your dependence on them is purely
gratuitous and but it's it's real as
such because you never question it and
you never try to go against it so so in
that sense by developing strength
through self control one becomes
with the like more strength means more
contentment